

SUMMARY

Frontend software engineer with a passion for clean code and DRY principles. Javascript developer with experience working on a fully distributed team while designing, building, testing, and deploying solutions empathetic to client needs. Specialties include React, Typescript, ES6, and beyond. Former professional Broadway actor of 10 years totaling over 2,300 live performances from New York to Las Vegas. Excellent communicator with over 5 years experience mentoring young artists and athletes in both one-on-one and group settings.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, HTML, CSS, NodeJS, SQL

LIBRARIES AND FRAMEWORKS: React, Redux, Express, Flask, jQuery, Jest, React Testing Library, Bootstrap, Material UI

TOOLS: Git, AWS, PostgreSQL, VSCode, Heroku, Netlify, Jira

SOFT SKILLS: Public Speaking, Flexibility, Collaboration, Attention to detail

EXPERIENCE

Zephyrx November 2021 - Current

Software Engineer · Remote

- · Led a team that rapidly deployed bespoke client solutions while instituting pair programming and code review, resulting in improved feature stability
- Oversaw conversion of React codebase from Javascript to Typescript, reducing reports of bugs in production
- · Constructed real-time video interface with AWS Kinesis and WebRTC, expanding clinical access to and usage of our real-time coaching feature
- · Formalized development processes by writing a company style guide, leading to more concise version histories and clarifying expectations

Associate Software Engineer · Remote

May 2021 - November 2021

- · Assisted in implementation of real-time video and messaging via Amazon Chime, facilitating use of our dashboard for remote appointments
- · Improved data flow by leveraging React-Redux to refactor state management, resulting in reduced page load times
- · Empowered our client services department by building out administrative tools, significantly reducing development team support workload

Technical Engineer, Jr. · Remote

November 2020 - May 2021

- Added accessibility for 20+ new languages, resulting in international use of our provider dashboard
- Supported QA team by developing a unit test suite and documentation, contributing to a single communication close rate over 75%
- Ensured production stability by coordinating testing of web and mobile components, improving team understanding of product

Springboard, Software Engineering Career Track

Student

April 2020 - September 2020

- 700+ hours of hands-on course material
- 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight
- Completion of 4 in-depth portfolio projects
- · Mastered skills in front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, data structures and algorithms

Jersey Boys Actor · New York, NY August 2015 - March 2020

- Acted in over 1,500 performances of this ubiquitous Broadway Show
- Took action to save 7,800 ticket refunds over 4 performances by stepping in for duties outside of job scope

PROJECTS

Lyrify 2020

Lyrics for Spotify listeners

- Crafted a responsive single-page app with React, Redux, and Material UI components working with a Node / Express backend
- Followed Oauth2 protocol for login via Spotify and consumed multiple 3rd party APIs for data aggregation with PostgreSQL
- Improved MVP by adding custom search with input sanitization to increase rate of positive results

The Easy Meal 2020

Discover recipes, construct and email yourself a grocery list

- Built Flask Python backend serving dynamic Jinja HTML templates, and a UI responsively styled with bootstrap and custom CSS
- · Secured against CSRF with form validation, and applied bcrypt authentication for user registration and login
- Consumed 3rd party API to access over 380,000 recipes, and cached recipe data with PostgreSQL to reduce API calls.

Jobly 2020

Mock job-seeking website

- · Developed a RESTful API with Node / Express, and a modular UI for this single page React app
- Built and validated forms with Formik and JSONSchema, and managed data with PostgreSQL
- Followed JWT standard for user authentication and authorization

EDUCATION

Springboard 2020 Software Engineering Career Track Certification Emerson College BFA Musical Theatre 2011 Cum Laude. Dean Scholarship Recipient